NETFLIX オリジナルシリーズ
Someone has entered the Area?
（黒瀬(くろせ)）
エリア内に何者かが入った？
Did they go over Aimoto Dam?
愛本遮断堰(あいもとしゃだんぜき)を乗り越えてか？
一時的に開放された？
どこの情報だ？
It was opened briefly?
Where did you get that from?
対策本部のサーバー？
The Matter Defense server?
But Nanbara said nobody can get in.
何が“何人(なんぴと)たりとも”だ
南原(なんばら)ちゃん
Just talking to myself.
いや こっちの話
Sorry for the trouble.
わざわざ悪かったな
I know. Yes, I know very well. Good night.
分かってる 分かってますって
じゃあ おやすみ
There isn't much I can do.
とはいえ…
Yuya and the rest
just left Yanagawara Camp,
雄哉(ゆうや)たちは
柳河原(やながわら)キャンプを出たばかりで
連絡が取れんか…
so I can't contact them.
Yes!
（楓(かえで)）ひゃっほ〜！
You silly Matter!
マターちゃんってば
コンペなんだから
もっと 張り切ってくんないと！
This is a competition!
You have to try harder!
Kaede! Don't assume Evidence is right!
（遙香(はるか)）
楓！
エビデンスをうのみにしないで
ほいほ〜い！
Yeah, I know!
She sure is having fun.
She's forgotten she's the diversion.
（一樹(かずき)）
楽しそうでいいですね
陽動係だってのも忘れて
I'm getting sick of facing
the same damn stuff all the time!
そろそろ似たようなのばっか
飽きてきたんですけど〜
Misawa!
（篠山(しのやま)）三沢(みさわ)！
（楓）あっ！
Kaede!
（遙香）楓！
ヤバッ！
Crap!
（相模(さがみ)）チッ
Damn it!
〜
（相模）
調子に乗るのも
いいかげんにしろ！
Enough of you
getting carried away!
（相模）マターの注意をそらす役が―
（アイコ）あっ
Your job is to distract the Matter,
not to put the Beetle in danger.
Damn it!
逆に ビートルを
危険にさらしてどうする！
クライアントと
仲良くお散歩だけじゃ
Just going on strolls with the client
won't score you any points either, right?
そっちも点数 稼げないでしょ？
I'm sorry.
（遙香）ごめんなさい
楓に有効な情報を提供できなかった
私のせいでもあるわ
It's my fault for not supplying Kaede
with effective information.
We'd never seen that kind of
Matter variation before!
（楓）
あんなマターの変形
今までなかったじゃん！
We couldn't have known...
予測なんて…
（遙香）
楓がスタンドプレーに走るのは
予測できた
I knew Kaede would show off.
パートナーとして
As her partner,
I should have controlled her better.
もっと的確に
コントロールすべきだった
Which means
you're still an inexperienced team.
（相模）
要するに
チームとして未熟ってわけだ
あっ…
く…
（白石(しらいし)）まずいわね
This is bad.
絡みついたマターが
アクチュエータの奥まで入り込んで
The Matter has entered the actuator
and crystallized.
結晶化してるわ
It's going to take a while to get it out.
取り除くのに
少し時間がかかりそう
（一樹）大丈夫ですか？
Will it be all right?
At sunrise tomorrow,
明日の日の出の時間になったら
the Matter around K2 will become active.
Ｋ２の門番が
活性化しはじめますよ
Judging from the timing,
（篠山）
月齢からして
門番の最大活性は１週間は続く
activity around the gate
will last a week.
If we get stopped for that long,
we'll run out of time.
それだけ足止めを食らえば
ミッションはタイムオーバーだ
（白石）急ぐわ
-I'll hurry.
-All right.
私は川上のマターを見張る
I'll watch the Matter on the river.
（一樹）何だよ あいつ
What's up with her?
I have a favor to ask, Minase.
（篠山）水瀬(みなせ)！ ひとつ頼めるか？
What is it?
（一樹）はい？
（アイコ）
三沢さんと芹(せり)さんの所 行ってくる
I'm going to Misawa and Seri.
Why?
（雄哉）何のために？
（アイコ）ひと言 声かけてくる
I want to thank them.
私たちのために
頑張ってもらってるんだもん
They're working hard to protect us.
（雄哉）ここにいろ
Stay here.
それで身を危険にさらして
If you put yourself in danger
彼女たちの仕事を増やせば
本末転倒だ
and cause more trouble, there's no point.
（ガション！）
Kazuki!
（アイコ）あっ 一樹さん
Aiko, are you all right?
アイコちゃん 平気だった？
私より…
三沢さんたち 大丈夫かな？
I'm more worried about Misawa and Seri.
（一樹）自業自得だよ
They'll get what they deserve.
おい！
Hey!
It's a sample of the crystallized Matter.
マターの結晶化サンプルだ
I heard from Shinoyama
篠山さんから聞いた
that you're chemically synthesizing
vial cartridges on the fly.
バイアルカートリッジを
即席で
ケミカルシンセサイズするって
Are you serious?
マジで言ってんのか？
（アイコ）ケミカルシンセ？
Chemical synthesis?
（一樹）
カートリッジの調合のことだよ
That's how cartridges are prepared.
（雄哉）
新手の情報を
タウンに持ち帰れない以上
If we can't deliver
this new data to Town,
シンセは ここでやるしかない
we have to synthesize it here.
お前 何者(なにもん)なんだ？
Who the hell are you?
Aren't you supposed
to not get involved with clients?
（雄哉）
クライアントには
深入りしないんじゃなかったのか？
く…
はあ…
あっ…
That guy really annoys me!
Who the hell does he think he is?
あいつ ホント マジムカつく！
偉そうに 何様？
He even involved you, Haruka!
遙香まで巻き添えにしてさ！
私は自分自身の非を謝罪しただけよ
I only apologized for my own mistakes.
遙香は何も悪くないじゃん！
You didn't do anything wrong!
このミッションが終わって
タウンに戻れたらさ
When this is over
and we return to Town,
you should partner with better people.
ちゃんとしたヤツと組み直しなよ
そうしてほしいの？ 楓は
Is that what you want, Kaede?
く…
（相模）
このままだと彼女は
If this keeps up,
いつか必ず 自分に足をすくわれる
she'll trip herself up someday for sure.
（篠山）
それも含めて コンペの評価対象だ
That's all part of our evaluation.
（一樹）くっそ！
Damn it!
あいつ 神崎(かんざき)って
If that Kanzaki wasn't our client,
I would never work with that jerk!
クライアントじゃなかったら
ぜってえ 会いたくないっすよ！
Dream contact?
ドリームコンタクト？
プライマリー･ポイントにいる
もう１人の君と
That's when your brain links with
your other brain located at Primary Point.
君の脳とを互いにリンクさせる
もう１人の君からの情報は
夢の形で君に入り込み
Information from the other you
is transmitted like a dream.
その夢を観察することで
By observing those dreams,
プライマリー･ポイントの状況を
のぞき込むことができる
I can see what's happening
at Primary Point.
もう１人の私と？
The other me?
（雄哉）心配はいらない
Don't worry.
すでに君は眠っている間に
数回 経験している
You have already experienced this
several times while sleeping.
前に 閉じ込められている
お母さんや弟君の今の様子を
You've seen
how your mother and brother are doing now
in your dreams, right?
夢で見たことがあるだろう？
それも
このドリームコンタクトの効果だ
That's part of this Dream Contact.
そっか
I see.
あの夢
もう１人の私が見た風景なんだ
Those dreams are what
the other me is seeing.
However,
（雄哉）ただし…
until now, these contacts
have been coincidental and passive.
今までのコンタクトは
偶然性に頼った
パッシブなものだった
今回 行うのは
This time,
このビートルの
演算処理能力を借りた
we will be using
the Beetle's processing unit
より精度が高く
to make a more precise and active contact.
能動性の強い
アクティブなコンタクトだ
ん？
（アイコ）私の脳をコピーして
My brain was copied,
私と同(おんな)じ思い出を持って
生み出されたもう１人の橘(たちばな)アイコ…
and there is another Aiko Tachibana
with the same memories as me.
どんな気持ちなんだろう
I wonder how she feels.
ん？ っていうか…
What? Wait a second!
You've been observing my dreams?
神崎君 私の夢のぞいてたの？
何それ！ ありえない！
By what right?
How could you?
ん？
だって 私の夢でしょ！
Those are my dreams!
If I knew you were going to
observe my dreams,
もう のぞくならのぞくって
先に言ってくれれば
恥ずかしい夢 見ないように
頑張ったのに！
I would've tried
not to have embarrassing ones!
いや 夢と言っても…
I'm calling them dreams,
もう１人の君の意識が
流れ込んできているだけだから
but they are only thoughts
from the other you.
（アイコ）ふーん
（南原）分かってる？
Do you get it?
There are other people
that must be placated.
手を打たなきゃならない相手は
ほかにもいるの
The Matter eradication wing?
（伊佐津(いさづ)）マター殲滅(せんめつ)派？
And abroad. This affects the economy,
internal affairs, and national security.
（南原）海の外にもよ
経済 内政干渉 国防…
いざとなったら 政府は
The government will use
destruction of the Area
to bargain, if necessary.
エリアの破棄をバーターに
しのごうとする
To protect Japan's
artificial organism industry,
この国の人工生体産業を守るには
強いカードが必要よ
we need an ace up our sleeve.
例えば…
For example,
新たな進化を遂げた人工生体が
showing the world that we've
already achieved
すでに完成している事実を
世に明かす
a new advancement in artificial organisms.
我々の勇み足を棚に上げてか？
You'd have us expose
the advantage we have?
（南原）
得られた魚の大きさを知れば
世間は口を慎まざるをえない
If people know the size of the fish,
we can't expect them to keep quiet.
そのためにも 唯一にして
最大の成果である橘アイコは
In order to accomplish this,
Aiko Tachibana, our greatest achievement,
絶対に失うわけにはいかないわ
must not be lost.
まったく
君の大胆さには感心する
Unbelievable.
You've got a hell of a lot of guts.
Of course I do.
（南原）ホントね
もし由良俊英(ゆらとしひで)がいれば
ここまでしなくても済んだのかも
If Toshihide Yura were still around,
this may not have been necessary.
He is already dead!
ヤツは もういない！
由良は もういないんだ
由良ノートなんてものも…
Yura is gone. And there is
no such thing as the Yura Notes.
That is exactly why
I will bring back Aiko Tachibana,
だからこそ
私は 必ず橘アイコを取り戻す
どんな手を使ってでもね
no matter what it takes.
こんなところで
終わるわけにはいかない
I can't let this end now.
SCHOOL ORIENTATION CEREMONY
MUSIC COMPETITION
What is this?
（雄哉）
ん？ 何だ？
What in the world is all this?
どういうことだ？ これは…
～
（アイコ）あっ…
Kanzaki.
（アイコ）神崎君…
お母さんと亮太(りょうた)に また会えた
由良先生にも
I saw Mom and Ryota again.
And Dr. Yura, too.
神崎君なら きっと知ってるよね？
由良先生
You must know Dr. Yura, right, Kanzaki?
Toshihide Yura...
由良… 俊英
（アイコ）
やっぱり…
お父さんが言ってたから
I thought so.
Dad even said,
若いけど
とっても優秀で有名な研究者だって
"He's young,
but he's a very famous researcher."
でも 私が会った由良先生は
そんな感じじゃなかったな
But the Dr. Yura
that I knew wasn't like that.
何だか つかみどころのない
不思議な人だった
He was rather elusive and mysterious.
でも おかしいな
That's strange.
私 由良先生と
あんな青空の下で会ったことない
I never saw Dr. Yura outdoors
under a blue sky like that.
お父さんの会社が
桐生(きりゅう)病院でやってた定期検査と
I only met him at the checkups
Dad's company did at Kiryu Hospital,
交通事故の手術のときだけ
and at the surgery after the accident.
もう１人の私だって…
Is that a dream
夢だから？
from the other me?
何か 別の人の思い出みたいだった
It seemed like the memories
of a different person.
（雄哉）疲れただろう
You must be tired.
The mingling of consciousness
during Dream Contact
ドリームコンタクトによる
主観意識の交錯は
脳に負担をかける
is hard on the brain.
しばらく休んでいたほうがいい
You should rest for a while.
（アイコ）
ううん 休んでなんかいられないよ
No, I can't rest.
Because,
だって
みんなが頑張ってるんだから
everyone is working so hard.
I have to work even harder.
私はもっと頑張らないと
私にもできることを何か…
There must be something I can do.
（グミ）キュキュイ
（アイコ）あっ！ あ…
Gummi!
（アイコ）グミ！
おなか減ってたんだ　ごめん
You must've been hungry. Sorry.
おいしい？
Is that good?
So, even your brain is
an artificial organism, right?
ねえ あんたって
その脳みそも人工生体なんだよね？
What are you thinking? What is it like?
ホント 何考えてんの？
どんな気分？
But you know,
those rations don't have any taste at all.
でも レーションって
ちょっぴり味気ないよね
そうだ！
I have an idea!
（ガタン）
うん？
Okay, we're ready to go.
（白石）お待たせ　すぐに出るわよ
あっ 白石さん！
Shiraishi!
（篠山）
エリア３にダイブインするためには
To get inside Area Three,
we absolutely must arrive at K2
before sunrise tomorrow.
何としても
明日の日の出時刻までに
Ｋ２に到達せねばならない
Everyone must keep that in mind!
各位 くれぐれも心してほしい
If I rehydrate this package,
（アイコ）
こっちのパックは 水で戻せば
it will be like mashed potatoes.
マッシュドポテトっぽく
なりそうだから
温めたチキンの
レーションの上にのっけて…
Then, I can add some heated chicken
おいしい食事で
みんなを応援したいか…
She's trying to raise morale
by making the meals delicious.
必要なのは 栄養素とエネルギーだ
All they need is nutrition and calories.
余計なことはいいから 席につけ
Forget about it. Sit back down.
（アイコ）けど…
（グミ）キュキュキュ
But...
Hey! Don't do that!
（アイコ）こら！ ダメだって
ん？
何だろう？ 何か… 来る！
This is odd.
It feels like something's coming.
あっ！
（２人）あっ！
Malignant!
（遙香）マリグナント！
Evidence!
（相模）エビデンス！
Golf 24 Iota!
（一樹）
ゴルフ･ツー･フォー･イオタ！
（遙香）
変種パターンが
これまでどおりならね
The mutations still keep coming.
Area Two positions!
（篠山）エリア２ポジション！
Misawa and Seri, divert the Matter!
マター陽動は三沢･芹！
ビートル警護は相模･水瀬！
Sagami and Minase, guard the Beetle!
（アイコ）あっ 何あれ！
What is that?
（白石）マターの天井よ
A Matter ceiling.
大丈夫
あのマターは ずっと休眠状態
It's okay.
That Matter has always been dormant.
（一樹）待った！
Wait!
It's active!
活性化してる！
-What?
（一同）えっ！
We're flanked above and below.
（相模）
上下から挟みうちってわけか
（篠山）
猶予はない このまま突っ切る！
Don't stop! Charge through!
We have to knock out whatever we can!
（楓）
片っ端から
つぶしゃいいってことでしょ！
Remember, this isn't your one-man show.
（相模）
いいな？
お前一人のショーじゃないぞ
Mind your business!
余計なお世話！
ヘヘッ… あっ！
結晶化… しない？
It's not crystallizing!
This mutation is different from before.
（遙香）
変種パターンが これまでと違う？
Is it a new type?
（雄哉）新種か！
-I'll hit it from the ceiling!
-Roger!
（楓）天井のほうから片づける！
（遙香）分かった
（遙香）活性度に気をつけて
Watch out for other activity!
（相模）このままだと
If this keeps up,
ビートルに攻撃が及ぶのも
時間の問題だ
it'll attack the Beetle before long.
自分がヘビーレーザーを！
I'll man the heavy laser.
了解！
Roger.
（白石）
ファイア･アシストをリンクする
I'll link the fire assist computer.
意識の中でターゲットを選択して
トリガーを引く
Focus on an object to target it,
then pull the trigger.
Got it?
いけるわね？
And this adjusts power and wavelength.
（雄哉）出力と波長はこれか
Here it comes again!
はっ… また！
（白石）アイコちゃん？
（アイコ）来る！ そっちから
-Aiko?
-It's coming! From over there!
うう… くっ！
Over there!
あっち！
-How can you tell?
-I don't know!
（雄哉）なぜ分かる？
（アイコ）分かんない
How come? How can I tell?
どうして… なんで分かるの？
The laser's vial cartridge
and Evidence aren't right!
レーザーもバイアルカートリッジも
エビデンスが合ってねえ！
None of our weapons are effective!
（遙香）
手持ち全種 有効弾がない！
If nothing is effective,
we may as well give up!
（楓）
適合すんのなきゃ
お手上げじゃん！
そうだ！ サンプルを！
I know! I'll get a sample!
撃たれたマターの破片があれば
I need a piece of Matter we've shot.
There's one!
あった！
（ピピピ…）
Got it!
きた！ わっ！
うわっ！
うぐっ！
ケミカルシンセ やってみせろよ！
Chemically synthesize this, Yuya Kanzaki!
神崎雄哉！
Got it!
受け取った！
私が代わりにレーザー砲を
I'll take over the laser cannon.
（白石）えっ？
（雄哉）じっとしてろ！
-What?
-Sit still!
That is your most important job!
それが 君がすべき
いちばんの仕事だ
I can't just sit still!
何もしないなんて できない
Shiraishi!
白石さん！
Patch me into everyone!
皆さんと通信をつなげてください
あっ…
（アイコ）あっ…
相模さん 上です！
Sagami, above you!
Thanks for that!
助かった
Haruka, behind you!
遙香さん 後ろ！
How did you know?
どうして？
（アイコ）篠山さん そっち！
Shinoyama, there!
Kaede!
楓さん！
（楓）
いいよ あんた面白いじゃん！
I like it! This is getting interesting!
I'll kick your butt now!
まとめて お相手してあげる！
（遙香）
１人で背負わないで 楓！
Don't attack it alone, Kaede!
But it's my fault
that we have to make up time!
（楓）
だって 私のせいで時間が…
取り戻さなくちゃ！
あっ！
It's active!
活性化！
うっ！
（相模）あっ
お前一人のショーじゃないぞ
This isn't your one-man show.
I can't help it.
This is how I've always done things.
しょうがないじゃん
ずっと こうやってきたんだから
Excellent! Now, just hold still!
（相模）
よし！
頼むから じっとしててくれよ
（遙香）楓！
Kaede!
（楓）
なんで？ ほっとけばいいじゃん
What? Why didn't you leave me?
I won't disgrace my name
（相模）名折れになるんだよ
俺がいる前で仲間に死なれちゃ
by letting one of my comrades die!
あっ…
（雄哉）完成した！
It's completed!
カートリッジは
無人のバイポッドに運ばせた
Cartridges loaded
onto an automated bipod!
（相模）了解！ 行くぜ！
Roger! Let's go!
All right!
（楓）よっ！
（楓）生き残ってやるわよ！
それで満足？
I'll stay alive! Will that satisfy you?
That's the spirit!
その調子だ！
ふん！
-Your arm!
-It's artificial anyway.
（遙香）ちょっ その腕…
（一樹）義手ですから
-It's crystallizing!
-Perfect!
（楓）結晶化する！
（相模）ドンピシャだ
はあ… すごい
Amazing!
They're all coming at the same time!
あっ 同時に！
（雄哉）あっ
（アイコ）あっ！
-Yes!
（２人）よし！
やったわ！
ん？ アイコちゃん？
We did it!
Wait, Aiko?
（雄哉）橘！
（白石）アイコちゃん！
-Tachibana!
-Aiko!
Are you okay?
（白石）大丈夫？
It's over.
終わったぞ
Thank goodness.
よかった…
（グミ）キュウ
What?
（黒瀬）ああ？
You have been dismissed.
（伊佐津）
君には除籍処分が下された
理事会の全会一致だ
当事者である君を除いてね
It was a unanimous vote by the board
of directors, except for you.
クビ？ 俺が？ なんで？
I've been fired? Why?
心当たりはあるだろう
Certainly, you must know why.
ありすぎて逆に分からんよ
どれだ？
I can think of many reasons.
Which one was it?
桐生先生の研究予算から
お前に流れた金の行き先について
With your use of funds
from Dr. Kiryu's research budget,
虚偽の記載が発覚した
we discovered falsified records.
桐生のおやじさんは？
What about Dr. Kiryu?
（伊佐津）
君の裁量に委ねてある旨
かばってはおられたが
He defended you by saying its use was
at your discretion.
我々としては
業務規定違反にあたる会計報告を
But we couldn't possibly ignore
the infraction of company rules
放置しておくことはできないのでね
in the accounting report.
残念だ
Too bad.
I messed up!
（黒瀬）しくった
With me out of the way,
nobody will block
俺をハブりゃ
ヤツが桐生研のトップに立つのを
whoever is running Kiryu Research.
邪魔するヤツはいない
The problem now is the old man's password.
問題は
おやじさんの持ってるキーコードだ
サーバーには
あのファイルが残ったままなんだ
Those files are still on the server.
あれが渡ったら…
If that stuff gets out...
（一樹）
まさか お前のケミカルシンセが
使い物になるとはな
I didn't expect your chemical synthesis
would come in handy.
It was thanks to the data you collected.
（雄哉）
君は採取したデータに従ったまでだ
腕まで直しやがって
ったく 何者だよ
You even made me a new arm.
Who the hell are you?
-How's it going?
-All done.
（遙香）どう？
（雄哉）終わった
（遙香）
どうして
マターの位置が分かったの？
How did you know
where the Matter was coming from?
なんで… かな？
I'm wondering, too.
Who cares about that? We won!
（楓）
いいじゃん そんなの
勝てたんだし！
And you made our rations taste great!
それにレーション
ここまで化けさせるなんてさ
すごいよ アイコ！
Way to go, Aiko!
You're right! This looks great!
ホント うまそう！
マターの察知に 意識の喪失…
She senses Matter,
but loses consciousness.
アクティブドリームコンタクトの
影響だろう
It must be the active Dream Contact.
ありえるの？
Is that possible?
可能性は十二分に
It's highly probable.
それと もう１つ 気になることが
Something else bothers me.
プライマリー･ポイントにいる―
It appears the other Aiko
at Primary Point is losing consciousness.
もう１人の橘アイコの意識レベルが
低下しているようだ
Really?
えっ？
It's likely due
to all the recent activity.
おそらく 大活性の影響
急がないと たどりつく前に
If we don't hurry,
she may lose consciousness
before we arrive.
彼女が意識を
喪失してしまうかもしれない
そうなったら 交換手術は…
If she does,
the surgery won't be possible.
ん？
-What?
-What's wrong?
（一樹･遙香）ん？
（楓）どうしたの？
（相模）あっ…
（相模）マリグナント！
Malignant!
Everyone, prepare for action!
（篠山）各位 対処準備！
Wait! There's something
on the close-range sensor!
（白石）
待って 近接センサーに別の反応！
（一同）あっ！
Heat source at five o'clock!
５時！ 種別 動力熱源！
（２人）あっ！
〜
Subtitle translation by Brian Athey